Mandar Deshmukh

Full Stack Web Developer

mandardeshmukh.mud@gmail.com +918087352864 Thane, Maharashtra 421503

Professional Summary

Full-Stack Web Developer with **2 years of experience** building performant, user-focused web apps using **React, Node.js, Express.js** and **MySQL**. Delivered key **fintech features** like **configurable UI systems** and **advanced session management**. Strong in system design, modular architecture, and solving complex product challenges in high-paced environments.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript | Frontend: React.js, HTML, CSS | Backend: Node.js, Express.js | Databases: MongoDB, MySQL | Tools: Git, Github, VSCode, Postman, Figma | Others: REST APIs, Redux, Redux-toolkit, Chakra UI, Styled Components

Work Experience

Hyperface Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Application Engineer - 2

04/2024 – Present Bangalore, Karnataka

- Led the **redesign of session management**, transitioning from account-level to **customer-level sessions**, enabling seamless account switching without login interruptions.
- Implemented session logic in CBCC-PWA (Co-branded Credit Card), IndusInd CardsHub and IndusInd-Journeys improving user experience and system efficiency.
- Abstracted and modularized the session management logic into a shared **NPM library**, promoting reuse and simplifying future maintenance across multiple applications.
- **Designed and implemented multi-card flow** in **CBCC-PWA**, allowing users to manage and switch between multiple co-branded credit cards with a unified, intuitive interface.

Hyperface Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Application Engineer - 1

05/2023 – 03/2024 Bangalore, Karnataka

- Developed key frontend features for the company's CBCC PWA, Onboarding PWA AND IndusInd CardsHub, using React.js, TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js.
- Built dynamic UI components for: **Spend Analytics, Festive UI, Benefits Section** (CVP, Campaign, Merchant offers each with distinct UI), **Rewards & Cashbacks, Nudges UI**
- Enabled a configurable UI system for CBCC-PWA, where teams can set: Themes, UI Order, UI Version, and API Auth all controlled via a central dashboard.

Education

University of Mumbai Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical Engineering)	07/2016 - 07/2019
Government Polytechnic Thane Diploma in Engineering (Mechanical Engineering)	08/2013 - 07/2016

Certifications

Masai School 08/2022 - 04/2023

Full Stack Web Devlopment ∂